二零一五年税務修訂第二號條例草案。
本會現在恢復為二零一五年仲裁修訂條例草案嘅二讀辯論。
啊！
深意上述嘅條例草案嘅委員會主席梁繼昌議員會就委員會嘅報告向本會發言，梁繼昌議員。
先生，主席，在我作為主席委員會主席的職能下，
我報告了 deliberations of the Bills Committee。
The Bills Committee supports the Arbitration Amendment Bill 2015.
which seeks to make it clear that parties opting for domestic arbitration and specifying the number of arbitrators in an arbitration agreement.
may still retain their rights by virtue of Section 100 of the Arbitration Ordinance, Cap 609.
to seek assistance from courts for matters set out in section two to section seven of Schedule Two of the Ordinance.
And update for the purpose of the ordinance, the list of parties to the Convention on the Recognition and Enforcement of Foreign Arbitral Awards, 1958.
refer to as the New York Convention.
by adding the new parties, namely Bhutan, Burundi and Guana.
By adding British Virgin Islands to the entry for the United Kingdom, and by amending Bolivia to Bolivia, per national state of, in the schedule to the arbitration.
Parties to New York Convention Order, Cap 609 Sublegislation A。
委員會指出。
In order to remove the legal uncertainties relating to the opt-in mechanism provided for domestic arbitration under Part 11 of the Arbitration Ordinance.
It is necessary to, amongst other things.
Amend Section 23, 3 to clarify that.
If the parties fail to agree on the number of arbitrators in an arbitration, and Section 1 of Schedule 2 to the ordinance does not apply.
such number is to be either one or three.
As decided by the Hong Kong International Arbitration Centre.
B. amend section 102B, Roman letter two.
to remove the reference to section 1 of Schedule 2, so that section 100 does not apply only if the arbitration agreement has provided expressly that any of the provisions of Schedule 2, other than section 1, applies or does not apply.
and see.
Amend Section 1 of Schedule 2 so that for an arbitration to which Section 1 of Schedule 2 applies.
任何 dispute arising between the parties to the arbitration agreement concerned.
是 to be submitted to a sole arbitrator for arbitration.
如果 parties 失敗， to agree on the number of arbitrators.
The Bills Committee also notes that updating the list of State Parties to the New York Convention is to comply with obligations under the New York Convention to recognise and enforce arbitral awards made in contracting parties, so that arbitral awards made in new contracting states to the New York Convention.
such as Bhutan could be enforced by Hong Kong courts and vice versa.
委員會沒有提出反對在委員會階段提出的修改，由司法長官提出，將巴勒斯坦列入仲裁程序的安排。
parties to New York Convention order.
作為《state of Palestine》 acceded to the New York Convention on the 2nd of January 2005.
and has become a new contracting party to the convention on the 2nd of April 2005.
法案委員會，Mr. President， has not proposed to move any C S A to the amendment bill.
Next, Mr. President, I would like to give my personal views on this bill.
These days, arbitration has indeed become the most sensible option for individuals or companies wishing to settle a dispute.
gone are the days when threats to take legal action led to lengthy legal battles in a court of common law.
with often uncertain and very expensive outcomes.
even when a judgement is finally reached, this could then be followed.
by years of appeals and further litigation, and a difficulty to enforce the decision internationally.
arbitration is a much cheaper.
一更有效率的措施，來解決爭端。
它 finds solutions tailored to fit the problems of both sides.
And unlike.
a full litigation in courts.
once the decision is reached.
It is final.
There are further risks of litigation and no appeals.
國際仲裁有優勢，於進行爭議解決。
在一個中立的環境，與對比一個國家法院，有它自己的本地語言和法律。
those laws may not be developed for international commercial disputes.
The arbitration tribunal panel is made up of industry experts and lawyers who are independent of the parties.
Usually, between one and three panel members are selected through discussion and agreement between the parties.
The final decision of an arbitration panel is enforceable across the globe under the provisions of the New York Convention.
which has 149 nation signatories.
under arbitration， any proceedings remain completely confidential.
In order to protect any trade secrets or competitive practices from being made public.
Next, I would like to cover why Hong Kong is often chosen as a seat for arbitration.
And Hong Kong has the best facilities, indeed, and is the best location for the world for arbitration.
First of all, I think Hong Kong is accessible and well connected to all other major cities of the world.
好 transport links and advanced infrastructures make Hong Kong.
The international business preferred choice for arbitration.
香港國際機場是連接至超過180個全球目的地。
by more than a thousand daily flights.
可靠、 efficient， and reasonably priced.
香港的本地交通系統是世界級，which means that wherever one chooses to stay in the city, one is always conveniently placed.
香港的自由 visa 政策也意味著， nationals of over 170 countries can visit us without a visa.
This speeds up the process and reduces the cost for the parties involved, and is another important reason.
Why Hong Kong is such a popular choice for arbitration?
Also, Hong Kong's arbitration ordinance is the only legislation in Asia which adopts the latest version.
《》。
這意味著，一旦一個裁決已經由一個仲裁庭作出，
It is enforceable in over 150 countries.
The Hong Kong International Arbitration Centre also offers an expedite arbitration service.
which if all if all parties agrees to speed up the process.
The resolution can be done within six months.
There is also the opportunity for parties to apply for an emergency interim relief award of no more than 15 days.
在早期階段的HKIAC arbitrations。
作為國際爭執，香港亦特別地處境有利處理涉及中國的爭執。
And is widely acknowledged as the natural choice for such arbitrations.
Unlike many other arbitration locations and national courts.
香港 maintains an excellent track record of global enforcement.
特別係喺 Mainland China。
As well as signing up to the New York Convention, Hong Kong has also entered into separate arrangements on mutual enforcement awards with Mainland China and Macau.
perhaps the most important reason why Hong Kong is best suited for arbitration.
是 our independent legal system.
Our judiciaries, Mr. President, are amongst the most independent in the world.
and have a pro-arbitration attitude.
但，Mr. President。
我 must say this with a pinch of salt, because as you may be aware, there are a lot of pressures on the judiciaries these days, and I also hope that.
The fellow members, my honourable colleagues, in this chamber, can refrain.
from making absurd and groundless, you know, comments or criticism of the judiciary during their speech.
基本法的《Extra Jur》也保障了法院的終審獨立性，和，確實。
高等法院判決法官Law Millet。
Once commented in October last year that.
而喺佢十四年喺法庭上。
他從來沒有遇過任何外部的影響，從中國或任何地方。
他係驕傲地成為一箇世界上最強勁的上訴法院之一。
therefore, once an award has been made by an arbitration tribunal.
The courts in Hong Kong will enforce the award as a matter of common procedure.
The parties can rest assured that the court will not interfere or review an award once it has been made.
although the costs remain neutral and removed from the decision-making process.
They are able to offer assistance with the taking of evidence and by granting a time limit extension for an arbitral tribunal to issue an award.
They can also support the work of the arbitration panel by offering legal advice.
作為我們的法律制度，完美地適應仲裁。
We also have a wide range of quality professional services available, with 70 of the largest.
有The largest hundred banks operating here， and sixty five of the top hundred global law firms operating in Hong Kong.
When choosing independent industry and legal experts to sit on the tribunal panel,
The Hong Kong International Arbitration Centre provides lists of highly experienced arbitrators from a wide range of sectors.
For industry-specific advice, Hong Kong has a wealth of talent, including 29,000 qualified engineers.
37,000 accountants。
more than 8,500 members of the Hong Kong Institute of Surveyors.
and over 4,000 architects.
在律 legal profession。
We have 7,800 practicing solicitors.
和1,200 barristers。
In addition.
more than 1,400 foreign lawyers qualified in over 29 different overseas jurisdictions practice law in Hong Kong.
Outside Europe and North America.
The Hong Kong International Arbitration Centre is most experienced in the world.
它 handles around 450 disburseals every year.
And in 2014 alone, 93% of those disputes were international cases.
With the total value, under arbitration reaches a total of 2.4 billion US dollars.
with all these as the background, I think I would urge the members across the spectrum to support the amendment bill. Thank you, Mr. President.有冇其他言上發言？
如果冇嘅，我現在請就請律政司司長發言答辯。喺司長發答辯之後，辯論即告結束。律政司司長。
代主席，首先我感謝2015年仲裁修訂條例草案法案委員會主席梁繼昌議員同埋其他委員嘅努力，令到相關審議工作順利完成。我亦都要感謝各有關嘅團體，包括係香港大律師公會、香港。
律師會、香港測量師學會同埋香港國際仲裁中心提供嘅寶貴意見。
正如我今年二月向本會提交條例草案嘅時候指出，呢一條條例草案嘅主要目的係修訂《仲裁條例》第六百零九章，以消除該條例因為第十一部為本地仲裁而設嘅可供選用機制。
制可能引起不明確嘅法律問題，因此我哋建議修訂仲裁條例，以清楚定明選擇本地仲裁嘅當事人可以自由決定仲裁員嘅人數，但係同時保留相關。
當事人就仲裁條例附表二第二至第七條載述嘅事宜，向特區原眾法庭尋求協助嘅權利。
條例草案亦會響《仲裁紐約公約替約方令》，亦即係第六百零九章附屬法例A附表中加入一九五八年承認及執行外國仲裁裁決公約，簡稱《紐約公約》四個新嘅替約。
方此外，條例草案提出嘅建議修訂，亦都會反映紐約公約一個現有替藥方嘅官方名稱有所更新，同埋另一現有替藥方將該公約嘅適用範圍擴展到去該。
公誒替約方嘅一個領土，因應紐約公約替約方名單嘅新近變動，我稍後會響全體委員會審議階段動議一項修正案。法案委員會知悉該修正案嘅內容，亦都冇提出反對嘅。
嘅意見。
律政司一直係致力提升香港作為亞太區國際法律及解決爭議服務中心嘅地位。
自現行嘅仲裁條例喺二零一一年實施以後，我哋一直係同仲裁界同埋其他持份者保持緊密嘅溝通，適時對條例、對仲裁條例作出修改。
條例草案獲得通過之後，將會有效改善為本地仲裁而設嘅可供選用機制，從而進一步完善香港嘅仲裁製度。主席，我僅此陳辭，肯請各位議員支持通過二讀條例草案。
以及我稍後動議嘅一項修正案，多謝主席。我現在向各位提出嘅代決議題係《二零一五年仲裁修訂條例草案》予以議讀，現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
二零一五年仲裁修訂條例草案，全體委員會審議階段，本會現在成為全體委。